<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking and the Internet</title>
    <link>https://csc4200.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Networking and the Internet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://csc4200.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Material</title>
      <link>https://csc4200.github.io/material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csc4200.github.io/material/</guid>
      <description>Textbook We will be using the following book. It is open source and you can use PDF or the EPUB version. You can also view the HTML pages here.
Title: Computer Networks: A Systems Approach Authors: Larry Peterson and Bruce Davie Copyright: Elsevier, 2012 Source: https://github.com/SystemsApproach License: CC BY 4.0  Raspberry Pi - We will be using Raspberry PIs for the third project. You will need to buy one but you get to keep it at the end of the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your own content delivery network</title>
      <link>https://csc4200.github.io/programming3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csc4200.github.io/programming3/</guid>
      <description>Due Date - November 27, 2019, 10PM CST Objectives
 Learn to break down a very complex problem into smaller problems
 Solve each smaller problem and bring them together to solve the larger problem
 Learn how CDNs work and build your own CDN
  Overview


In this project, you are going to build on the first and the second project. You will build your own &amp;ldquo;CDN load-balancer&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Assignment</title>
      <link>https://csc4200.github.io/programming1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csc4200.github.io/programming1/</guid>
      <description>Due Date - Sept 13, 2019 Objectives
 Learn to create network packets.
 Learn how packets can be sent over the network.
 Familiarize you with the concept of sockets.
 Learn packing structures, endianness, unpacking, and interpreting network data.
 Learn how to use actual data from a packet.
 Use packet capture to visually inspect protocols.
Overview

In this warmup project, you are going to implement a client and a server program that will send a command over the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://csc4200.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csc4200.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>This is a tentative schedule and will change.
Week 1 - August 26, 28, 30 - Introduction, Network terminologies, Architecture vs Protocols - Lecture 1, Lecture 2, Lecture 3
September 2 - Labor day, no class
Week 2 - September 4, 6 - Connecting machines, Reliable Delivery, Ethernet, Access protocols Lecture 4, Lecture5, Lecture 6 September 8 - Last date to drop class
Week 3 - September 9, 11, 13 - Link layer continued</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To the Cloud and Back</title>
      <link>https://csc4200.github.io/programming2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csc4200.github.io/programming2/</guid>
      <description>Due Date - October 20, 2019, 10PM CST Objectives
 Learn to create robust network protocols
 Learn about reliable communication
 How a premitive proxy might work. You can use this to get around sensorship or firewalls.
  Overview

In this project, you are going to build on the first project. You will have a server in the cloud that downloads and saves a web page in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>